<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="MaduraHTML.xsl"?>
<doc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://maduradocs.googlecode.com/files/MaduraDoc_5.0.6.xsd">
	<title>
		<MainTitle>madura-dbloader</MainTitle>
		<SubTitle>User Guide</SubTitle>
		<Author>Roger Parkinson</Author>
		<Revision>$Revision$</Revision>
		<image>logo.jpg</image>
		<references>
			<reference t="maduradocs" url="http://code.google.com/p/maduradocs/" />
			<reference t="Apache Licence 2.0" url="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0" />
		</references>
	</title>
	<body>
		<process-log/>
		<process-references/>
		<h1 t="Overview">
		<p>This is an ant task that will run multiple sql files using potentially multiple schemas. It is intended
		for use during development rather than production for those times when DBAs release a new load of database scripts
		and you need to update your local database. Normally you would use the <courier>sql</courier> task but that
		does not handle multiple schemas as well as this.</p>
		<p>So, if you have a database that spans multiple schemas and you need to run multiple scripts against them all then MaduraDBLoad
		will help.</p>
		</h1>
		<h1 t="Ant">
		<p>This is what you add to your ant file:</p>
		<code><![CDATA[
<target name="load">
	<taskdef name="dbloader" classname="nz.co.senanque.dbloader.RunDatabaseScripts">
	  <classpath>
	  	<fileset dir="${basedir}/lib" includes="*.jar" />
	  </classpath>
	</taskdef>
	<dbloader 
		dir="${scripts.dir}" 
		driver="${jdbc.driver}" 
		drop="true" 
		debug="false" 
		jdbcURL="${jdbc.url}" 
		systemPassword="${system.password}"/>
</target>
	]]></code>
	<p>If you set 'drop' to false it will not drop and rebuild the schemas, otherwise it will.</p>
	<p>Other options not shown here are:</p>
	<list>
	<ll name="defaultTableSpace">Current default is USER.</ll>
	<ll name="systemUser">Current default is 'system' which is fine for Oracle, maybe not other databases.</ll>
	<ll name="delimiter">Used to find the schema name in the script file name. Default is dash ('-').</ll>
	<ll name="ignoreConstraints">default=false, if true then no foreign key constraints will be created.</ll>
	</list>
	</h1>
	<h1 t="SQL Scripts">
	<p>The sql scripts should have names like this:</p>
	<code><![CDATA[
	001-MYSCHEMA1-create_schema1_tables.sql
	002-MYSCHEMA2-create_schema2_tables.sql
	003-MYSCHEMA3-create_schema3_tables.sql
	004-MYSCHEMA1-load_test_data.sql
	005-MYSCHEMA2-load_test_data.sql
	]]></code>
	<p>So there are five sql files. These ones have a simple number on the front to determine the order but you
	can choose any arrangement that works for you, as long as the names sort into the order you want them to run.</p>
	<p>The schemas are identified by the surrounding dashes. Notice that we use underbars as word separators elsewhere,
	though actually only the first two dashes will be looked at to identify the schema.</p>
	<p>Schemas found will be dropped and recreated before we start unless you specify drop=false.</p>
	<p>Lines starting with '--' '#' 'exit' 'commit' 'set' 'prompt' are ignored in the SQL file, the whole
	file is surrounded by a start transaction and commit.</p>
	<p>Functions need to be terminated with a slash (/) like this:</p>
	<code><![CDATA[
  CREATE OR REPLACE FUNCTION "MYFUNCTION" (ID NUMBER) RETURN VARCHAR2 IS
...
/
	]]></code>
	<p>Same with triggers and procedures. Otherwise the commands must end with a semicolon (;).</p>
	</h1>
	<a1 t="Release Notes">
		<table width="12cm">
			<tw>12cm</tw>
		<tr>
			<th>1.5</th>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>Added pom file.</td>
		</tr>
        <tr>
            <th>1.4</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Build for java 1.7.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <th>1.3</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>Tidying the build.</td>
        </tr>
		<tr>
			<th>1.2</th>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>Ignore files where we cannot find a schema name, but continue with other files.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<th>1.1</th>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>Optionally disable creation of foreign key constraints. Flag is 'ignoreConstraints'</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>Line based comments now supported, as well as correctly handling comment-like structures in quotes.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>Handle lone semicolons with no associated statement.</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<th>1.0</th>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>Initial version</td>
		</tr>
		</table>
	</a1>
	</body>
	
</doc>
